import type { MCQ } from '../../../types'

export const mcqSet8: MCQ[] = [
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of statistics?",
    "options": [
      "Data visualization",
      "Data summarization",
      "Data collection",
      "Data transformation"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question": "Which type of data do Business Intelligence systems primarily work with?",
    "options": [
      "Real-time data only",
      "Historical data only",
      "Real-time and historical data",
      "Future predictions only"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "Which of the following refers to the speed at which new data is generated and processed in big data?",
    "options": [
      "Volume",
      "Variety",
      "Velocity",
      "Veracity"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question": "In which industry is big data used for predictive analytics and personalized medicine?",
    "options": [
      "Retail",
      "Finance",
      "Healthcare",
      "Manufacturing"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question": "What makes the integration of big data sets complicated?",
    "options": [
      "Data volume only",
      "Data variety and velocity",
      "Data storage capacity",
      "Data processing speed"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "What is the main focus of machine learning?",
    "options": [
      "Identifying patterns in data to make predictions or decisions",
      "Storing large amounts of data",
      "Visualizing data trends",
      "Collecting data from various sources"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a main type of machine learning?",
    "options": [
      "Supervised Learning",
      "Unsupervised Learning",
      "Reinforcement Learning",
      "Recurrent Learning"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "What is the first step in the machine learning life cycle?",
    "options": [
      "Gathering Data",
      "Data Preparation",
      "Model Training",
      "Evaluation"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question": "What percentage of time do data scientists typically spend on data engineering tasks?",
    "options": [
      "30-40%",
      "50-60%",
      "70-80%",
      "90-100%"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question": "Which programming language is commonly used by data engineers for ETL tasks?",
    "options": [
      "Java",
      "Python",
      "C++",
      "Ruby"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  }
]
